# Molly Kizer

Full-Stack Web Developer

**Portfolio** GitHub Profile

# CONTACT

(207) 404 - 6030

molly.kizer@qmail.com

28 Crediford Road Wells, ME 04090

in linkedin.com/in/mollyrkizer

# SKILLS

#### **TECHNICAL**

HTML & CSS

**JavaScript** 

Python

**j**Query

Node.js

#### **TOOLS**

Git & GitHub

Visual Studio Code

Anaconda

Bootstrap, Materialize

### PROFILE

A quick-learning, self-motivated full-stack web developer with experience building dynamic and responsive web applications both on my own and as part of a team.

A mediator (INFP) on the Myers-Briggs scale, able to listen and empathize with others to understand their perspectives and needs to design and improve the functionality and UX of apps.

## EDUCATION

- Certificate: Full-Stack Web Development (in progress)
  UNH Professional Development and Training
- **Certificate.** Intro to CS & Programming w/ Python
- **Master's in Teaching,** concentration Life Science University of Maine, Orono 2013 - 2014
- **Bachelor's of Arts, Psychology** Boston University 2000 - 2004

# **PROJECTS**

# HIGH CARD PICKS DINNER

Deployed App, Code Repository

Fully responsive app; allows the users to compete to pick dinner and provides recipes to search through. **Tech used:** HTML, CSS, Materialize, JavaScript, jQuery, Moment.js, Animate.CSS, Chart.js, and multiple API calls.

## WEATHER DASHBOARD

Deployed App; Code Repository

Displays current weather and five day forecast for any city in the world.

**Tech used:** HTML, CSS, Bulma, JavaScript, jQuery, jQueryUí, Moment.js, and multiple API calls (OpenWeather API)

#### DAILY PLANNER

<u>Deployed App;</u> <u>Code Repository</u> <u>A daily calendar that provides a way for a user to plan their work day; saves calendar input in local storage.</u> **Tech used:** HTML, JavaScript, jQuery, Moment.js

# Molly**Kizer**

# TRANSFERABLE SKILLS

#### Attention to detail

- Carefully reviewed student work to provide detailed feedback.
- Diligent about creating presentations and assignments that were clear and free from errors.

# Verbal and written communication

 Clearly communicated with students, parents, teachers, and administrators throughout the day.

# Teaching

- Explained difficult science concepts to students with a wide variety of skill sets.
- Trained other teachers to use digital tools in the classroom.

# Presentation skills / Public Speaking

- Daily presentations of material to students.
- Occasional presentation of work to other teachers and administrators.

# Collaboration / Teamwork

- Frequently worked with other teachers to design or improve lessons and assessments.

# RECENT WORK HISTORY

# HIGH SCHOOL SCIENCE TEACHER

SANFORD HIGH SCHOOL & REGIONAL TECHNICAL CENTER

Planned lessons and presentations both independently and collaboratively to teach Physical Science and Biology to students.

- Constantly assessed student understanding and adapted future lessons based on results.
- Collected and analyzed student feedback to provide more relevant and interesting lessons.
- Communicated with students, and parents when necessary, to ensure clarify what was necessary to succeed.
- Experimented with a variety of computer-based technologies to engage students and improve instruction.

# HIGH SCHOOL SCIENCE TEACHER

NOKOMIS REGIONAL HIGH SCHOOL

- Continuously collected student input to tailor instruction to their needs and interests.
- Researched and evaluated the effectiveness of new student engagement strategies.

# BEHAVIORAL HEALTH PROFESSIONAL

UNITED CEREBRAL PALSY OF MAINE

Provided support and guidance to children and their families to improve their functioning at home and in the community.

 Made careful observations and took detailed notes to share with other providers.

# **ORGANIC FARMER**

A VARIETY OF FARMS THROUGHOUT MAINE

- Educated the community about local organic food and plant care through work at farmers markets.
- Utilized knowledge of plant and ecosystem biology to design farm plots and successfully grow fruits and vegetables.

**M** 

2016

2014

2017 - PRESENT

2011 - 2013

- 2011

2009